Clinton YongQiang Law

Mobile: +65 9853 7435

Email: clintonlaw@u.nus.edu

Skype: live:.cid.1e7477bcc4a9873a
Online Resume URL: https://clawyq.github.io/

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/clinton-law-80350718b/

GitHub: https://github.com/clawyq/



Personal Statement

About Me

The rags-to-riches fairytale that is the life of Jack Ma harbours many attributes that resonate greatly within me. While I am no Jack Ma, I too possess a problem-solving acumen and an unrivalled work ethic. I am a strong believer of Maya Angelou's famous quip, that "nothing will work unless you do", and understand that problem solving can only get me so far – the rest is supplemented by getting my hands dirty and putting in the work. During my stint at Capitaland, I achieved what my manager branded as "The Impossible" – pick up the slack of data cleansing and completed a year's worth of work within 3 months. Despite not knowing anything about data cleansing nor Excel when I first joined, I was able to quickly pick it up to and wrote effective macros to automate workflows. Despite the sheer volume of work, I understood that the onus was on me to deliver – I had no qualms regularly working on weekends and sometimes through the night.

I am also hungry and proactive in ceasing opportunities – I am wary to never get too comfortable with what I have, fuelling my drive for constant self-improvement. I recognise that there learning extends way beyond academics, and actively strive to gain exposure to skills and technological stacks that I believe will be useful for my career. In my previous summer stint at a start-up called treatsure, I would independently research on features and architectural design patterns that will aid the company going forward and proactively suggest them to my CTO – thereby allowing me to learn them in the process. Fast forward to now in the current semester, where most students will do a normal workload of 5 modules, I am currently taking 4 modules, appointed a teaching assistant for 1 module, working 3 days a week at a self-sourced internship doing full-stack development, all while juggling 2 coding projects as part of my extracurricular activities. Again, I recognise the extra dilligence and discipline required for my commitments but am glad to have made this choice as this semester has been a fulfilling learning experience for me. Being so busy does not mean that I skimp on quality as well – I take extreme pride in all my work and have not put out an assignment that I am not proud of.

Internship Objectives

I am hoping to be challenged and stretched to fully capitalize on the amazing learning opportunity this internship presents. Through the exposure to different technological stacks and architectural design patterns all while working alongside talented individuals in a quickly iterating start-up, I hope to channel my skills into driving the growth of the start-up in both technical and business pursuits. I also hope to take away insights that extend well beyond the realms of technology and learn the nuances of what drives and make a successful startup.

How I Can Contribute

Through my various experiernces, I possess a versatile skillset with a unique edge that is geared towards building scalable software. Coupled with my familiarity with Azure's Cloud services, I can develop and deploy features at scale – an asset that I foresee might be helpful for fast iterating start-ups looking to ramp up their operations. My experience with numerous technological stacks will also allow me to ease in and quickly adapt to any software engineering roles,

Aside from technical skills, I am a great team-player who can effectively communicate and refine my ideas on the go. My cheerful and outgoing disposition will certainly allow me to ease into the company's environment, which further promotes a pleasant working environment.

Thank you for taking the time to read my personal statement and I look forward to working, and learning, with you.

Education

Ladoution		
Aug 2017 - Present	National University of Singapore Bachelor of Computing (Honours) in Computer Science (Course details in Appendix A)	Singapore
Aug 2017 – May 2019	 University Town College Programme Resident of Tembusu College Curriculum designed centered around coherency of general education with an emphasis on focused multidisciplinary learning Headed table tennis interest group Active member of TembuTech, the student technology interest group. 	Singapore
Jan 2009 - Dec 2014	 River Valley High School Singapore-Cambridge General Certificate of Education Advanced Level 	Singapore
Work Experience		
Aug 2019 – Present	 KeyReply Software Engineering Intern In charge of developing customer-facing features for a chatbot project for a call center managing calls hundreds of thousands of calls per month. Help to develop the analytics pipeline to optimise efficiency of workers. 	Singapore
Jan 2019 – Present	 National University of Singapore Undergraduate Teaching Assistant Prepared lesson materials and taught tutorials for CS2105 (Introduction to Computer Networks) for both the 2nd Semester of the 2018 Academic Year and the 1st Semester of the 2019 Academic Year. Beat out departmental averages for teaching scores. 	Singapore
May 2019 – Aug 2091	 treatsure Software Engineering Intern Overhauled previously monolithic backend and to adhere to scalable it in accordance to the Microservice architectures using Node, gRPC and Azure. Implemented unit and integration tests with Mocha and Postman. Implemented payment features with Braintree to automate the process payment related procedures to serve a customer base of 10,000 users. 	Singapore
May 2018 – Aug 2018	 Accenture Data Migration Analyst Automated the testing and cleansing of several millions of rows of data for 20+ business entities for a project; some scripts are still used today. Worked with clients to architect data templates to facilitate the migration process. Managed data in several SAP modules to ensure the successful migration of data into the production environment. 	Singapore
Apr 2017 – Aug 2017	 CapitaLand Data Analyst Picked up Excel and developed VBA Macros and in-workbook scripts to cleanse several million rows of data from 20+ Business Units. Coordinated different project divisions to organise data in preparation for migration to the new SAP environment. 	Singapore

Scholastic Achievements/Extracurricular Activities

Aug 2019 - Present en:code Singapore Software Developer Architect, design and build technological solutions for social causes. Currently building an e-receipt application for an education center catered for children from less fortunate backgrounds Aug 2019 - Present 180 Degrees Consulting Singapore Technology & Operations Analyst Led development of the organisation's future IT architecture based on diverse strategic priorities Developed an implementation plan for the organisation's medium term future Integrating project management toolkits on a centralised app to improve productivity and coordination Aug 2019 **Tertiary Infotech** Singapore Raspberry Pi Essential Training Attained a certificate of achievement May 2019 Bits & Bolts Hackathon 2019 Singapore Best Artificial Intelligence My team and I bested 20+ other teams and designed a computer vision centric prototype built on top of OpenCV that was able to perform crowd localisation in enclosed spaces. Aug 2017 **Inter-Faculty Games (Table Tennis)** Singapore Competed alongside my fellow peers from the School of Computing and landed a 3rd place finish against teams from other faculties in NUS.

Skill Sets & Proficiency

Skill Sets & Proficiency			
Development tools	Node.js, Express.js Vue, Vuex HTML, CSS gRPC Microsoft Azure Mocha Postman Kubernetes GraphQL React	Proficient Proficient Intermediate Basic	
Database	MSSQL	Intermediate	
Programming Languages	Java JavaScript TypeScript Python C	Proficient Proficient Intermediate Intermediate Basic	
Hardware	RaspBerry Pi	Intermediate	
Office Productivity	Microsoft Word, PowerPoint, Excel	Proficient	
Languages	English Chinese	Fluent Fluent	

Degree: Bachelor of Computing (Honours) in Computer Science

Cumulative Average Point: 4.21 / 5.00

Year	Level	Course Description	Grades
Aug – Nov 2017	Year 1/Semester 1	CS1101S Programming Methodology	A-
		CS1231 Discrete Structures	S
		GER1000 Quantitative Reasoning	А
		MA1101R Linear Algebra 1	S
		UTW1001H Eating Right(s): The politics of food	B+
Jan – May 2018	Year 1/Semester 2	CS1010R Programming Methodology	A+
		CS2030 Programming Methodology II	A-
		CS2040 Data Structures and Algorithms	B+
		CS2100 Computer Organisation	B+
		MA1521 Calculus for Computing	B+
		UTC1112A Humanising Technology	CS
		UTW2001R Discourse, Citizenship and Society	B+
Aug – Nov 2018	Year 2/Semester 1	CP2106 Independent Software Development Project (Orbital)	CS
		CS2101 Effective Communication for Computing Professionals	S
		CS2103T Software Engineering	B+
		CS2105 Introduction to Computer Networks	A+
		CS2106 Introduction to Operating Systems	B+
		UTS2105 Singapore as 'Model' City?	A-
Jan – May 2019	Year 2/Semester 2	CS3230 Design and Analysis of Algorithms	C+
		CS3243 Introduction to Artificial Intelligence	B+
		ES2660 Communicating in the Information Age	A-
		IS1103 Innovations in Organisations and Society	A+
		ST2334 Probability and Statistics	В
		UTC2108 Technology and the Fate of Knowledge	A-
Aug – Nov 2019	Year 3/Semester 1	CS4248 Natural Language Processing	In- progress
		CS3103 Computer Networks Practice	In- progress
		CS3244 Machine Learning	In- progress
		ST2137 Computer Aided Data Analysis	In- progress

NUS Grading Scale:

A+ & A (5.0); A- (4.5); B+ (4.0); B (3.5); B- (3.0); C+ (2.5); C (2.0); D+ (1.5); D (1.0); F (0)

S = Satisfactory; U = Unsatisfactory

CS = Completed Satisfactorily; CU = Completed Unsatisfactorily

EXE = Exempted; IC = Incomplete; IP = In Progress; W = Withdrawn